<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Pasig Landmark &#8211; Sample Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/mergalo1/destinations/pasig-landmark/feed/?simply_static_page=1069" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://jamesrolandv.github.io/mergalo1</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 11:05:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://jamesrolandv.github.io/mergalo1/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/MERGALO.png</url>
	<title>Pasig Landmark &#8211; Sample Blog</title>
	<link>https://jamesrolandv.github.io/mergalo1</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Notable Landmarks in Pasig City</title>
		<link>https://jamesrolandv.github.io/mergalo1/2024/05/21/notable-landmarks-in-pasig-city/</link>
					<comments>https://jamesrolandv.github.io/mergalo1/2024/05/21/notable-landmarks-in-pasig-city/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[james]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 13:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Landmark]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jamesrolandv.github.io/mergalo1/?p=92</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A highly urbanized city in Metro Manila, there’s no question that Pasig City is filled with landmarks. But skyscrapers aside, there are some historical structures worth mentioning within the city itself. Pasig was once a rural settlement, but slowly evolved into a residential and industrial sector. Over the past few years, it has seen itself [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A highly urbanized city in Metro Manila, there’s no question that Pasig City is filled with landmarks. But skyscrapers aside, there are some historical structures worth mentioning within the city itself.</p>



<p>Pasig was once a rural settlement, but slowly evolved into a residential and industrial sector. Over the past few years, it has seen itself develop into a commercial center, largely thanks to the establishment of the Ortigas Center Business District on the eastern side of the city.</p>



<div class="wp-block-media-text is-stacked-on-mobile is-style-default"><figure class="wp-block-media-text__media"><img decoding="async" src="https://triptheislands.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Ortigas_Center_Manila.jpg.webp" alt="Ortigas_Center_Manila" class="wp-image-9707 size-full"/></figure><div class="wp-block-media-text__content">
<p>Not far from the NAIA Airport in Pasay City, getting to and from there to the city isn’t that much of an inconvenience, traffic conditions aside.</p>
</div></div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">NOTABLE LANDMARKS</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>MERALCO</strong>&nbsp;– even before the construction of the Ortigas Center in the 1960s, the Meralco building was one of the most noticeable structures in town. Mostly, it was due to its close proximity to EDSA Shrine, which has been a site of too many a political movement. The building houses the offices of the Manila Electric Company and during Christmas time becomes a spectacle itself due to its unique display.</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><strong>ULTRA </strong>– also known as the University of Life Theater and <a href="https://triptheislands.com/destinations/5-of-the-best-luxury-hotels-in-mindanao/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Recreational Area</a>. It is now better known as the Philippine Sports Arena and is where different sporting events, as well as local and international concerts have been held. It was established in 1975 and original facilities, especially the oval and the swimming pool, still remain and are preferred training grounds of athletes.</li>
</ul>



<div class="wp-block-media-text is-stacked-on-mobile"><figure class="wp-block-media-text__media"><img decoding="async" src="https://triptheislands.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/1024px-Ph-mm-pasig-city_proper-immaculate_concepcion_cathedral_2015.jpg.webp" alt="immaculate concepcion cathedral" class="wp-image-12567 size-full"/></figure><div class="wp-block-media-text__content">
<p style="font-size:clamp(14px, 0.875rem + ((1vw - 3.2px) * 0.078), 15px);"><strong>Immaculate Conception Cathedral </strong>– established at around the same time the town was founded in 1573. The Roman Catholic Church is better known as the Pasig Cathedral and is the oldest structure in the city. The church that stands today is a restored one as the original structure suffered damage during the August 1968 earthquake. It was converted into a cathedral on October 2003.</p>
</div></div>



<ul>
<li><strong>Mutya ng Pasig Public Market</strong>&nbsp;– spanning three stories, this is said to be the largest public market in the country. There are more than 2,000 fixed stalls as well as another 2,000 plus used in the flea market on weekends.</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><strong>Tektite Towers</strong>&nbsp;– built in 1993 for the Unified Philippine Stock Exchange. The 34-storey twin towers offer great views of Ortigas Center.</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><strong>Beaterio de Pasig and Chapel&nbsp;</strong>– the remnants of the old chapel of the Beaterio de Santa Rita, or as it’s more popularly known, the Beaterio de Pasig. It was established in 1740 and became a stronghold during the British invasion of 1762. It was heavily damages by the 1880 earthquake and was renovated in the 1960s. Only the facade is what remains of the original chapel.</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><strong>Bahay Na Tisa</strong>&nbsp;– an ancestral home that has been passed on in the Tech family for many generations. It was built by Don Cecilio Tech y Cabrera during the early 1850s. It was called Freedom House during Martial Law and was used for many meetings.</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><strong>Cuartel del Guardia Civil</strong>&nbsp;– better known as the Guanio Residence. It was built in 1881 and converted into a prison for captive Katipuneros. The Guanios then acquired the place.</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><strong>Pasig City Museum</strong>&nbsp;– this was formerly the Concepcion Mansion and was built by Don Fortunato Concepcion in 1937. The Japanese used this as their headquarters and it’s also where the Americans hoisted their flag as a sign of freedom from the Japanese. It was acquired in 1980 by the City of Pasig and was used to house the&nbsp;<a href="https://triptheislands.com/featured-stories/museo-sugbo-from-provincial-jail-to-historical-museum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">museum of the city</a>.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://triptheislands.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/pasig-city-museum.jpg.webp" alt="pasig city museum" class="wp-image-12566" title="9 Landmarks of Pasig City 4"/></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jamesrolandv.github.io/mergalo1/2024/05/21/notable-landmarks-in-pasig-city/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
